Navigation
----------

Privacy Policy
--------------

This privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) is a component of the Terms of Service Agreement (“Agreement”) you agree to when using our Services, Game, and websites. To view the entire Terms of Service Agreement, visit [https://pokemmo.com/tos/](https://pokemmo.com/tos/)

We recommend that you review the entire Agreement at the same time. We use some capitalized terms in this document which are defined in the main policy document.

1\. What does this Privacy Policy cover?
----------------------------------------

This Privacy Policy tells you what to expect when we collect personal information. It applies to information we collect about:

* Your usage of our websites, [https://pokemmo.com/](https://pokemmo.com/), [https://forums.pokemmo.com/](https://forums.pokemmo.com/), [https://translate.pokemmo.com/](https://translate.pokemmo.com/), [https://support.pokemmo.com/](https://support.pokemmo.com/), and any other website we provide
* The Game (“PokeMMO”)
* Any other Service we provide

This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and cannot control, activities which occur when you click a link to a website we don’t operate (“external site”). If you visit an external site which is linked from one of our websites or through the Game, we highly recommend that you review the privacy policy of that site before you provide any personally identifiable information.

The personal information you provide may be transferred to, stored, and processed within the United States or other countries where we maintain business operations (see Section 8 (“International Transfer”) for more information).

By using this website, the Game, or any other Service, you acknowledge the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you object to anything described in this Privacy Policy, please do not use our websites or play the Game. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes. As with the Agreement, if we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting the change on our websites or in this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the websites, Game, or Services will signify that you acknowledge these changes.

2\. Who is processing your information?
---------------------------------------

PokeMMO (referred to as “The Company”, “us”, “we”, or “our” in this document and the rest of the Agreement), is the data controller for the processing of your personal information.

3\. What types of information do we collect?
--------------------------------------------

We may collect different types of information from you depending on how you use our Services, including Personal Information. “Personal Information” means information that relates to an identified or identifiable natural person.

Examples of Personal Information we may collect include:

* Email address(es)
* Approximate Date of Birth, as indicated by your acceptance that you are over the age of 13 when entering this Agreement
* Language and other information about location
* Billing, payment, and financial data
* Account information such as account name, account identification number, external account key, account activity, and account change activity
* In-game and external purchase/transactions history
* Contest entry information
* Game activity information such as character name, gameplay progression, friend lists, friend requests, and in-game chat
* Game identifiers such as Account ID and Character ID(s)
* Game file version(s)
* Device ID, Device Key, MAC address, IP address, and Unique Hardware Identifier(s)
* Device operating system name, operating system version, device environment details, and system specifications
* GeoIP information
* Internet browser provider and type
* Pages visited on our websites
* Marketing information such as mailings receiving, mailings opened, newsletter sign-up information

In addition to the above, we may also collect information that does not generally identify you but may become associated with your account. We reserve the right to use information that does not generally identify you in connection with any lawful purpose.

4\. Where do we collect Personal Information?
---------------------------------------------

We collect information from or about you in the following ways:

1. From you. We may collect your Personal Information when you provide it to us directly through the Services you use. For example, when you:
    1. Register for an Account, contest, or giveaway
    2. Submit additional information to us when prompted by us
    3. Order Premium Game Content
    4. Send email messages to us, submit forms, or contact us through our websites
    5. Respond to surveys, customer questionnaires, or when reading newsletters we publish
    6. Interact with the customer support team, including when you report problems
    7. Play the Game
    8. Register for participation in an event we run
2. From Third Parties. We may also receive Personal Information from or through certain third-party services which we partner with to help us provide the Services and/or facilitate your access to the Services, including, by way of example, our Payment Providers used to facilitate payments to us.

5\. What Third Parties collect Personal Information on our behalf?
------------------------------------------------------------------

1. Payment Processors. For security reasons and to better protect your privacy, we do not directly collect or store your payment information and are only able to access limited information concerning payment methods and transactions. Should you choose to make a purchase for Premium Game Content or Reward Points, we use third-party payment processors who collect payment information on our behalf to process your transactions. Specifically, payment, billing and credit card verification services may need to collect certain Personal Information in order to access your payment methods and process your transactions. If you choose not to provide Personal Information for payment processing needs, they will not be able to complete your requested transaction(s) on our behalf. We may receive Personal Information from our Payment Providers about you if you request support from them, such as if you directly ask a Payment Provider for a refund.
2. Analytics Partners. We may receive Personal Information about you from third-party analytics partners which helps us understand the website or link which brought you to one of our websites. For example, if you click on a link while using a search engine that directs you to one of our Services, we may receive information such as your subsequent account creation and downloads.

6\. Why do we collect Personal Information?
-------------------------------------------

The following provides examples of the purposes for which we may use your Personal Information:

| Context | Types of Data | Primary Purpose for Collection and Use of Data |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Account Activity | We collect information such as your IP address, email address, approximate age, and game-related information when you create an Account. We also collect information relating to the actions you perform while logged into your Account. | We use this information to perform our contract to provide you with the Game and Services. We also have a legitimate interest in providing Account related functionalities to our users. Accounts can be used to save your preferences, play the Game, and keep transaction history. |
| Communications / Chat Logs / Content Posting | When you communicate through a Service, the Game, or other chat rooms we operate, even privately, we process, store, and may monitor those communications to detect cheating, fraud, illegal activity, or other activities that may violate this Agreement. | We have a legitimate interest in ensuring the security of our Services, detecting illegal activity, and . We also have a legitimate interest in responding to communications that we receive. In limited circumstances, we may use this information to protect your or another person’s safety. |
| Cookies and First Party Tracking | We use cookies for necessary website operations, such as when you log into a website we operate. | We have a legitimate interest in making our website operate efficiently. |
| Cookies and Third Party Tracking | We use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect analytics information about your use of our Services. Where required by law, we base the use of third party cookies upon consent. | We have a legitimate interest in receiving, and acting upon, information pertaining to your use of the websites. |
| Customer Support / Feedback | If you inquire or provide us feedback through a contact panel, we may collect your name and email address, or information pertaining to your logged in account, as well as any other content that you send to us, in order to process your inquiry and/or reply to you. | We have a legitimate interest in receiving, and acting upon, your feedback or issues. In some circumstances, we use your information to perform our contract to provide you with products or services. |
| Error Logs & Diagnostics | We collect information such as your IP address, Game account ID, device information, and game-related information when you submit an error log to us. We also collect software version information of software we provide (the Game Client and other Game Software) when you login or start the Game Client. | We use this information to fix program bugs and errors. Among other things, we also use this information to monitor our networks for fraudulent activity and to provide customer support to you. |
| Demographic Information | We collect information such as your approximate age, location, and language. | We use this information to ensure compliance with this Agreement. We also have a legitimate interest in understanding our users and providing tailored services. |
| Email Interconnectivity | If you receive email from us, we use certain tools to capture data related to when you open our message and click on any links or banners it contains. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding how you interact with our communications to you. |
| Gameplay | We collect your Personal Information such as, but not limited to, email address, in-game activity logs, and chat logs to provide you with the Game. | We use this information to perform our contract to provide you with products or services. We also have a legitimate interest in optimizing our users’ experience, identifying and fixing program bugs and errors, and preventing fraud and cheating. |
| Location Information | When you use our Services, we may collect your location from the GPS, Wi-Fi, and/or cellular technology in your device to determine your location. | We have a legitimate interest in keeping our Services secure, understanding our users, providing tailored services, and detecting and preventing fraud or illegal activity. In some contexts our use is also based upon your consent to provide us with geolocation information. |
| Mailing List | When you sign up for one of our mailing lists, we collect your email address and/or other information that allows us to communicate with you. | We have a legitimate interest in sharing information about our products or services. |
| Mobile Devices | We may collect information from your mobile device such as unique identifying information broadcast from your device when visiting our website. | We have a legitimate interest in identifying unique visitors, and in understanding how users interact with us on their mobile devices. |
| Sweepstakes or Contests | When you participate in a sweepstakes or contest, we may collect information about you which includes contact information to notify you if you are selected. | We have a legitimate interest in operating sweepstakes. |
| Testing / Early Access Programs | We collect Personal Information as part of our testing and early access programs (e.g. the Public Test Server) | We have a legitimate interest in making sure our products are secure and error free. We may also use this information to perform our contract to provide you with products or services. |
| Website Interactions | We use technology to monitor how you interact with our Services. This may include which links you click on, or information that you type into our online forms. This may also include information about your device or browser. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding how you interact with our Services to better improve it, to understand your preferences and interests in order to select and provide offerings that you might prefer, and to understand the efficacy of our marketing campaigns. We also have a legitimate interest in detecting and preventing fraud, and detecting and fixing program bugs and errors. |
| Web Logs | We collect information, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, domain name, click-activity, referring website, and/or a date/time stamp for visitors. | We have a legitimate interest in monitoring our networks and the visitors to our Services. Among other things, it helps us detect and fix program bugs and errors. |

7\. With whom may we share your Personal Information?
-----------------------------------------------------

1. Third Parties.
    
    We never sell your Personal Information to third parties for any reason, and we don’t share Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. However, we may need to share your Personal Information with third-party vendors that are subject to contractual and legal limitations on how they may use Personal Information they process for our business operations and interests. These limitations generally prohibit vendors from using Personal Information for any purpose other than the purpose for which it was provided or collected.
    
    When we share Personal Information with third-party vendors, we do so to provide you with access to the Game and other Services, and to administer, improve, present, and market our Services and business. The categories of third-party vendors that we may disclose Personal Information to include the following:
    
    1. Consultants, attorneys and similar vendors that are obligated to keep Personal Information secure and confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them
    2. Customer attribution (e.g. website analytics) services
    3. Customer support vendors
    4. Fraud detection and management services, authentication services, and vendors that assist us with managing other risks associated with our business
    5. Marketing and advertising platforms and marketing companies, including vendors that help us manage contests, sweepstakes, surveys, and similar promotional events
    6. Moderation (i.e. Game / Forums moderation) and user experience providers
    7. Payment Providers which we partner with to process payments and to follow up with customer support inquiries
    8. Social media websites and email providers
2. Other Parties.
    
    We may disclose your Personal Information to other parties in the following circumstances:
    
    1. In response to law enforcement or other government authorities in connection with criminal, fraud, infringement, or other investigations related to suspected illegal activities
    2. To protect the safety of our players, including you, and our personnel
    3. To protect our legitimate legal and business interests

8\. International Transfer
--------------------------

We may store or process your Personal Information outside of the country where we collect it or which you reside. Our primary place of business is in the United States of America. When you use our Services and the Game, you should understand that we may transfer some or all of your Personal Information to the United States of America or other countries where we maintain facilities or business operations to carry out certain operational and processing needs as described in this Policy. You should understand that you are choosing to transmit your data to us and the country which the data is transferred to may not offer the same level of privacy protection as your own country.

9\. How is my Personal Information protected?
---------------------------------------------

1. Retention, Purpose Limitation, and Security Policies. We protect your Personal Information through a combination of collection, security, and retention policies:
    1. Limited Retention. We only keep your Personal Information for as long as we need it for business and operational needs or to comply with any statutory, regulatory, or legal obligations. We determine the retention period for each of the categories of personal information listed above based on: (1) The length of time we need to retain the information to achieve our business objectives for which it was obtained; (2) Any legal or regulatory requirements applicable to such information; (3) Internal operational needs; (4) Any need for the information based on any actual or anticipated investigation or litigation.
    2. Purpose Limitation. We will use your Personal Information only for the Services you choose to access or for our marketing purposes.
    3. Security Measures. We use appropriate measures to keep the Personal Information we collect and use in a secure environment, and we have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures designed to protect Personal Information from unauthorized access, disclosure, use, and modification. Our personnel are contractually obligated to only access your Personal Information when a breach of this Agreement is suspected, when it’s necessary to perform development or debugging, or when a customer support request has been made by you. As part of our privacy compliance processes, we review these security procedures on an ongoing basis to consider new technology and methods as necessary. However, please understand that our implementation of security measures as described in this Privacy Policy does not guarantee the security of your Personal Information.
2. Your Practices and Activities. Your practices and activities are likewise very important in the protection of your own Personal Information. You can take certain steps to help protect your Personal Information, such as being mindful of what you post in public places:
    1. Do not use your real name when selecting an Account name or character name. When using the Services, the name you choose may be visible to other users of the Services, such as when you use our Forums or when you play the Game.
    2. Do not post your real name in public-facing areas of the Services, such as the Forums, Game chat, or chat rooms we operate, and do not share anything private about yourself on such public platforms, including your phone number or address. Use your character name or other public-facing username instead of real names at all times.
    3. Many types of communications, especially those on public forums or social media, are generally available to the public or large groups of unknown users. Remember that we have no control over what third parties do with the content of such communications and we have no responsibility or obligation regarding third parties’ collection or use of communications you share. You are solely responsible for content you post in public forums at all times.

10\. Cookie Policy
------------------

1. Cookies and Tracking Pixels. When you visit one of our websites, we may ask your browser to store a “cookie”, which is a small text file, on your device to remember information about you, such as your language preference or login information. We and our third-party providers use cookies to assign a unique number that automatically identifies your computer when you visit our websites. Some cookies remain on your computer until you delete them; others, like session ID cookies, may expire when you close your browser. We and our third-party providers also use other identifiers (such as Clear GIFs, pixels, web beacons) to track the pages visited on our websites or the emails and other communication we send. Such tracking identifiers are tiny graphics that are embedded invisibly on web pages or in HTML-based emails. Please be aware that we do not currently recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include "Do Not Track" instructions.
2. Purposes. We use cookies and other tracking technologies for the following purposes:
    1. To assist you in navigating our websites or to display certain types of content;
    2. To log in to certain features or to provide us your feedback;
    3. Analyzing your use of our Services, functionality and use of our pages and links, collecting aggregated user data, and traffic sources; and
    4. Tracking and analyzing our promotional and marketing efforts.
3. Third Party Cookies. Some cookies on our websites come from third-party advertisers or analytics providers. We work with third-party advertising and analytics providers to help collect information about website visitors and account holders and their usage of our Services. Those third-party providers may use cookies and tracking identifiers to collect, and may otherwise have access to, information about users of our Services, including Personal Information. For example, third-party providers may collect or otherwise have access to usage information (e.g. information about the pages where users enter and exit our websites, what pages they view on our websites, etc.), device information, online identifiers of users, and demographic and interest-level information.
4. YouTube. Our websites may use YouTube to store and show video content. YouTube serves cookies to help us provide the video content, but does not collect or process your information for advertising or analytics purposes.
5. Cloudflare. Our websites may use Cloudflare for load balancing and to better provide you service. Cloudflare may serve cookies to facilitate load balancing.
6. Other Third Party Cookies. In addition to the third party cookies listed above, we may use cookies from other companies to help improve our services for you.
7. Browser Settings; Choices about Cookies. You may set your browser setting to attempt to reject the cookies and tracking identifiers, and you may still use our websites. However, you may be limited in some areas of our websites, or you may have to enter passwords or identifying information more than once.

11\. What rights do you have to your Personal Information?
----------------------------------------------------------

1. Right to Access, Correct, Delete, or Restrict Processing.
    
    Subject to any limitations under applicable law, you may be able to exercise a number of rights:
    
    1. You may have the right to request access to your Personal Information. To assist you with understanding the data we collect about you when using the Game, we offer a private data export tool available at [https://support.pokemmo.com/export](https://support.pokemmo.com/export).
    2. You may have the right to request deletion of your Account and related Personal Information. If you choose to have your Personal Information removed from our active databases, we will carry out your request within 30 days of account verification and will only retain minimal information to document your request and the actions we took to carry out your request.
    3. We will comply with your rights requests in accordance with, and subject to, applicable law.
    
    To the maximum extent permitted by law, we reserve the right to refuse your request to delete your personally identifiable information if, for business operation purposes, we maintain a legitimate interest in continuing to process your information. For purposes of explanation, we maintain legitimate interest in your information in certain situations, such as if:
    
    1. You’ve previously breached this Agreement and your Account is not in good standing;
    2. You have a Dispute or other legal claim with us which has not yet been settled;
    3. You have an outstanding balance due to a chargeback, or you have an order made to our Payment Providers which has not yet been settled; or
    4. We believe your request is abusive, fraudulent, or unlawful.
    
    Please note that we are legally prohibited from carrying out requested actions in some instances, including:
    
    1. When we are unable to confirm your identity;
    2. Where the request is considered excessive, abusive, or fraudulent; or
    3. When doing so would adversely affect the rights or freedoms of other individuals.
2. Deletion Procedures
    
    After entering this Agreement and creating an Account, you may request your personally identifiable information be deleted by using the customer support panel, available at [https://support.pokemmo.com/](https://support.pokemmo.com/).
    
    You acknowledge that if you request your personally identifiable information be deleted, and we agree to that request, this Agreement and your Account(s) will be permanently and irrevocably terminated, and you will forfeit any Reward Points, Premium Game Content, or other Game Content associated with your Account(s). You will not be able to enter into this Agreement again, and you will not be able to play the Game anymore.
    
3. Right to Lodge a Complaint
    
    You have the right to lodge a complaint regarding our collection, processing, or storage of your Personal Information with a data protection supervisory authority in the country where you live or work.

12\. Special Categories related to Personal Information
-------------------------------------------------------

1. Children under 13. Our services are not designed for children under the age of 13. We do not intentionally collect, maintain, or disclose any Personal Information from children under the age of 13, and children under 13 are ineligible to create an Account or enter this Agreement. If you are a parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 who has submitted Personal Information, you can submit a removal request by sending us an email at [\[email protected\]](https://pokemmo.eu/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). If you do so, please provide all information pertaining to accounts created by your child, including the account names and email addresses used. If your child has bought any Premium Game Content or Reward Points from us, you may also request a refund at the same time.

13\. Contact Us
---------------

If you have a question or concern about your Personal Information collected:

* You can contact us via email at [\[email protected\]](https://pokemmo.eu/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* You can contact us via the support panel using your Game Account’s login details, at [https://support.pokemmo.com/](https://support.pokemmo.com/)

Copyright © 2024 All rights reserved.  
Use of this website signifies your agreement to the [Terms of Service](https://pokemmo.eu/en/tos/).  
PokeMMO is not affiliated or associated with any other company.  
All logos, trademarks, and trade names used herein are the property of their respective owners.
